NANDA KISHORE REDDY MANGUNURI

Leicester, England, UK | +44 7555114093 | nanda.mangunuri@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A recent post-graduate and a software development engineer with three years of experience in the technological field including digital banking and financial services mobile and web app development. Consistently acknowledged as a competent and hands-on developer. A diligent, organized, and attentive employee. Works fast to fulfil tight deadlines. An enthusiastic team member and eager to contribute to the success of the organization.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, StokBox

Mar 2022 - Nov 2022, Leicester, UK

- Designed and developed a web application using Python Flask framework and HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for a Raspberry Pi-controlled supermarket product dispensing technical solutions.
- Worked on the backend of the application by performing simple queries on the sqlite3 database.
- Utilized JavaScript and AJAX to update a portion of a webpage.
- Deployed the project into Azure using the GIT source control system.
- Involved in analysis and design of the application features.
- Collaborated and blended with respective teams in most phases of the project including Design, Development, Deployment, Testing and Implementation by having a greater flexibility.

Software Engineer, <u>TEMENOS</u> (Formerly, Kony Labs) Jun 2019 - Nov 2020, Hyderabad, India

- Handled and worked on front end web and mobile application developments in a real-time digital bank project including retail and corporate features.
- Followed Agile development and consistently delivered new features on time during sprints along with an understanding of TDD and BDD approaches.
- Generated web service requests through SOAP and raw XML and parsed the responses.
- Worked along with various teams on responsive web design.
- Involved in designing the user interface for iPhone and Android mobile apps.
- Involved in JS Coding and web service integration using Mobile fabric for the entire application.
- Handled application issues during UAT support.
- Cut data processing time by 50% by removing unnecessary API calls.
- Integrated File Download APIs implementation in Kony Application.
- Trained and motivated team of 5 on how to work with MVC during the development of applications.

Associate Trainee, <u>TEMENOS</u> (Formerly, Kony Labs)

Jun 2018 - Nov 2019, Hyderabad, India

- Worked on mobile application development in a real-time digital banking project.
- Committed to delivering quality code adhering to the coding standards and with minimal defects.
- Ensured that content met or exceeded business and client requirements 100% of the time.
- Debugged and troubleshot service requests and responses using the Fiddler tool.
- Involved in bug fixing in SIT and UAT phases.
- Tracked and fixed many issues with good code debug knowledge.
- Participated flexibly in fast-paced development cycles; completed 100% of deadlines ahead of schedule.
- Managed application code using bitbucket and various source control systems.
- Handled various API calls through asynchronous programming using JavaScript.

EDUCATION

University of Leicester

Leicester, UK

Master of Science in Advanced Computer Science with Industry; Distinction, 74% January 2023

B. V. Raju Institute of Technology

Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering; Distinction, 9.64 GPA

July 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Skills: Python, C, C++ and Java.
- Web Development Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), JSON, jQuery, AJAX.
- Frameworks: Django and Flask.
- Database: Oracle SQL, SQLite, MySQL.
- Tracking and Version Control Tools: Git, JIRA, GitHub, Bitbucket and SVN.

SOFT SKILLS

- Adaptive: Always flexible and able to adapt to whatever changes happen without losing the focus on goals.
- Interpersonal: Exhibit understanding and respect of others to achieve and maintain a harmonious working relationship.
- Leadership: Led many team building activities and able to establish a good communication and rapport with team members.
- Work habits: Accepted additional responsibilities following my experience and habituated to meet deadlines by collaborating with different teams.

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

Department Coordinator, BVRIT

Oct 2017 - Nov 2017, Hyderabad, India

- Coordinated and organised events at Promethean, a national-level technical symposium organized by our college, BVRIT.
- Managed finances for 10+ events involving ticket and voucher purchases.
- Created long-term and short-term agendas and planning activities for each event organizer meeting.

Student Representative, BVRIT

Aug 2015 - Jun 2018, Hyderabad, India

- Communicated with the module leaders and classmates.
- Discussed any problems from students & brought them forward to course leaders in meetings.

VOLUNTEERING

Student Volunteer, World Congress on Information Technology

Feb 2018, Hyderabad, India

- Assisted C-Level delegates from different parts of the world when signing in and out of the event.
- Processed temporary ID cards as needed.
- Supported information gathering by taking feedback from the delegates.

REFERENCES

Available on request.